consider a circuit consisting of a coil
characterized by the inductance L and
resistor R connected in serious then we
take a voltage source which provides a
voltage u0 as soon as we close the
circuit with the switch then a Time
dependent current I flows through the
coil and the resistor the current does
not have its maximum value immediately
but increases slowly due to Land's law
using kof's law we can set up the
following differential equation for the
current I remember that the point above
the I means the first time
derivative this is an inhomogeneous
linear differential equation of first
order the searched function y
corresponds here to the current I the
perturbation function s corresponds to
u/ L and is time independent in this
case we denote the homogeneous Solution
by
IH first we need to determine the
homogeneous solution IH we can quickly
calculate this using the solution
formula for the homogeneous version of
the differential equation that you
learned before the coefficient K in
front of the searched function I
corresponds to R over L and is also time
independent in this case so far so good
we may omit the constant CH in the
solution form formula here because we
consider it later anyway in the constant
a which we find in the other resolution
formula the coefficient R / L is
constant and integrating a constant only
introduces a variable T thus the
homogeneous solution is I is equal to e
to power of - R / L *
T let's insert it into the inhomogeneous
solution
formula note that one over the
exponential function containing a minus
in the exponent is simply equivalent to
the exponential function without the
minus sign now we have to calculate the
integral u/ L is a constant and can be
placed in front of the integral and when
integrating the exponential function the
exponential function is preserved only L
over R is added as a factor in front of
the exponential
function finally we hide the constant of
integration in the constant a and this
is our general solution we can simplify
it a bit more by multiplying out the
parentheses two exponential functions
simplify to
one to get a solution specific to the
problem we need to determine the unknown
constant a for that we need an initial
condition if we say that the time t
equal Z is the time when the current I
was Z because we have not yet closed the
switch then our initial condition is y
of 0 is equal to 0 insert it into the
general
solution e to the power of 0 is equal to
1 solve for a and you get a is equal to
- u0 / R thus we have successfully
determined the specific General
solution